dana.merrick@gmail.com San Francisco, CA – 978.206.1331

## HIGHLIGHTS

- Detail oriented, fast learner.
- Motivated problem solver.
- Superior communication skills.
- Technology generalist.

## COMPUTER SKILLS

Fluent: Ruby, Chef, AWS, shell scripting, SQL, JavaScript, Java.

Advanced: Git, PHP, C/C++, Perl, LATEX.

Proficient: Python, Go, Haskell, Clojure, Qt, AWK, Common Lisp.

Operating Systems: GNU/Linux, OS X, UNIX/BSD, ESX.

Expertise: Configuration management, automation, internal tools, backend design,

cloud architecture, scaling, networking, regular expressions, security.

### EXPERIENCE

Lead Infrastructure Engineer

May 2014-March 2015

IFTTT, San Francisco, CA

- Worked as sole infrastructure engineer responsible for servers on AWS and Heroku.
- Prepared for and oversaw the system during the launch of the Do apps.
  - The company's biggest launch to date.
  - Featured eight new apps, global press coverage, and millions of new users.
  - The entire launch week went impeccably.
- Managed a sophisticated job queuing system using Resque/Redis, which directed tremendous amounts of API traffic across nearly 200 different APIs.
- Updated Chef infrastructure to most recent version and best practices.
- Singlehandedly upgraded from Ruby 1.9 to Ruby 2.1 with no downtime.
- Cleaned up the codebase and the infrastructure from cruft, outdated/broken tools, and unnecessary costs.
- Countless improvements to monitoring and alerting tools, including PagerDuty, Pingdom, New Relic, Graphite, and CloudWatch.
- Improved stability of deploy process; reduced the total deploy time by 50%.
- Numerous speed and performance improvements across all areas of the stack.
- Dramatically reduced the frequency of incidents requiring human intervention.
- Contributed to many other areas of the company, including product design, marketing, community/support, and HQ operations.

# Platform Engineer

July 2011-May 2014

Zencoder / Brightcove, San Francisco, CA

- Lead the team responsible for replacing Brightcove's transcoding stack with Zencoder infrastructure.
- Managed build farm, Postgres databases, Riak servers, and Nagios monitoring.
- Migrated the AWS infrastructure to physical servers (and vice versa).
- Personally handled many long-term operations projects:
  - Allowed the AWS stack to run locally using Chef and Vagrant.
  - Automated building of machine images using Packer.
  - Modernized the Chef infrastructure using tools like Berkshelf and Foodcritic.
  - Upgraded Ruby from Ruby Enterprise 1.8.7 to Ruby 2.1.

## Brightcove, Boston, MA

- Worked on a team of engineers to design, build, and support a platform for cross-platform mobile development.
- Managed infrastructure configuration and deployment using Chef and AWS.

- Personally lead a team of engineers to completely overhaul the previous Chef infrastructure, including migrating hundreds of existing nodes.
- Supported multiple cross-region MongoDB replica sets and Resque queues.
- Participated in a 24/7 on-call support rotation.
- Designed and built Ruby on Rails application features and code.

## Software Engineer

July 2010-July 2011

BCM (formerly Backchannelmedia), Boston, MA

- Lead a small team of Ruby developers in designing, building, and launching a Rails 3 daily deal site: "Hazzoo.com."
- Personally handled entire Rails deploy and release management process using Engine Yard, Heroku, and AWS.
- Oversaw the completion, deployment, and maintenance of a pair of Rails applications for an interactive TV project: "Clickable TV.com."
- Earned a reputation as the resident Git expert; provided lessons, presentations, and advice on getting the most out of SCM in day-to-day development.

# Web Software Developer

Summer 2009

Wieck Media, Dallas, TX

- Pure Ruby development; contributing to the company's in-house web framework (and Rails alternative), called "Harbor."
- Designed and developed libraries (gems) for user, media, and release management, including a heavy focus on i18n for an international client.

## System Administrator

Summers/Holidays 2006-2009

Integrated Computer Solutions, Bedford, MA

- Managed the server infrastructure for all of the in-house machines, including production servers, personal work stations, virtual machines, and legacy hardware.
- Built server monitoring system, cared for physical servers, contributed to and maintained software.
- Developed features in PHP for their sister company's project management suite, called "Project.net."
- Helped a team of UI designers create tools to manage offshore workers and a full-featured online timecard system.

## **EDUCATION**

Trinity College, Hartford, CT

May 2010

Bachelor of Science, Double Major

Computer Science & Classical Mathematics Founding member: Hartford area Ruby group

## **PORTFOLIO**

My GitHub account has many public repositories for you to browse.

The most up-to-date version of this résumé can also be found there.

You may find it at github.com/dmerrick.

**LOOKING FOR** Opportunity to be rewarded for innovation and leadership.

Camaraderie with an intelligent team.

Adoption of modern technologies.

## REFERENCES

Available upon request.